Hi, and that was on, I want to show you how to work with ride mode in Cascade.
Cascade right mode works like auto GPT.
It can create files, run scripts, tests, and debug for you.
Just approach the checks and wait for it finished.
It automate about 90% of coding and debugging for you.
I did not let you make changes to multiple files at once in a one-shot prompt.
I did appear right in your editor, so you can review it and accept the client changes.
So you can also provide the relevant context and files for your prompt to be more accurate,
but I will cover it in the next lesson.
So now let's talk about some popular use cases for when you might need to use the ride mode.
For example, the first use case when you refactor parts of code of your application.
I know, imagine you have a big class and you want to split up all this functionality into separate methods,
so you can ask right mode for this case, you can just, okay, refactor this class just to lit up this
also logic inside of check method into separate methods or better maintenance, like you can ask, okay,
convert this class component into functions, for example, it's more useful like when you use
the when you have a React application, you can ask, okay, I want to migrate from class components to
functional components, for instance, you can ask about adding a new features.
If you have an application, you want to add a login form with validation.
You can ask in edit mode, add a login form with validation using React hooks.
You can ask, okay, implement dark mode toggle, for example, for your application,
it will add crazy needed files and implement it.
Now you can also fix the box, like if you're, I know, meta doesn't work or the logic
will work incorrectly, you can ask it, so like at least fix this method, I get some virtual
results.
For example, I know if like your application crash, you can also ask it, you can ask to
write unit tests, like I have this big class, so I want to ask, okay, this cover all this
matters by unit tests, and it will create a separate test file, it will add all the cases, and so it will be done for you.
For example, you can ask about improving the performance, like, I know, I use React application
and the application really slow, you can ask, okay, do some optimizations to load page faster,
so it might, you know, improve the performance and some of your hooks of functions, so
you can ask to optimize the API calls, like to use the new syntax or some library, for example,
or you can ask, ask to add some error handles in when you send, I know some requests to the backend.
Okay, let's now go into write mode in details, I have this big class with a lot of logic,
and I'm really lazy to create the unit test, so I want to ask also a wind source to do it for me,
so what I will do, I will just move the file right here as a kind of context, yeah,
and so write unit test, or this was over,
all the cases. Let's see what you'll do it.
Okay, it's generating something.
Okay, here's analyzing the class file,
here's analyzing all sorts of iterative files, so yeah, I guess not necessarily just to move
the file as a context, yeah, here's analyzing, but it's because our application is just two files,
so that's why he really easy understand, but if you have much more files, so you need to specify
a whole class, you want to write some unit test, as you see, analyze it all the files,
he's okay, he's gonna use just to write the test, we can also specify okay, what tools we want,
he will use to write the test, okay, and now it's providing some summary, what test he's creating,
so basic initialization with the password, okay, let's check method,
it checks, yeah, all the cases that our password has strong verification, common
password detection, some missing character types, etc, I check all the methods,
I check the very long password or an empty passwords, okay, he's also providing a common
for us, which we need to run, but it really, I don't know why it's not, but executable,
so let's check the settings, just get at the fixed links after execution, yeah, we can,
after execution, change the auto, I think, so let's see, so the auto mode model that
decides whenever to terminal, auto execute, premium models only,
and oh, turbo mode is always auto execute, terminal commands and browser controls,
except those things in the denial list, so we can set it to turbo,
okay, and let's see the difference, so we see right here, we created the test folder and a test file,
so we can click an open div, and we will see as a new file with all the test cases, we have
right here, it's not too many to be honest, okay, it's checked like one test, a lot of scenarios,
so we can click accept changes, right here, or reject, for example, we can click accept all,
right here, or reject all, what's the difference, if we, if you edited a multiple files,
and we click accept all or reject all in a cascade, so it will be applied for all the files,
you will see the context, but if we open a specific file, we can like accept changes or reject
for all the files, for example, if you have a few places, like in a file, you can just click accept,
or reject it just for the one block of the change, and for example, if there is a part of
what wasn't changed and below you have a new code, you will have also this section, okay,
let's click accept all, and so I'm lazy to copy this command, so, okay, I will ask, just run
those commands for me, and you will check how the auto running commands work, yeah, we see the
command was run, okay, he's created the package, the JSON file for our project, because we need to
store dependencies and the command somewhere, you see he created not modules folder with some libraries,
okay, I will open it one more time, yeah, okay, and we see he's running tests, yeah,
okay, yeah, he's finishing the installing dependencies, we see the package, load the JSON files with
all the dependencies of the libraries folder project, yeah, and now we see the package JSON file is
updated, install it, all the dependencies we need to run the project, so, and we have a lot of
multiple files right here, so we can see what was created and what was edited, and we can click
open deep right here for any of the file, like we said told you we can, yeah, can change this
over you, yeah, we can click and change this over you, we will see all the files were changed and how
my alliance was changed, we can click some additional options, it's not fast for now, okay, we see one
fillet thing, so he's trying to fix, yes, this is what my thing about the right mode,
if he had to defy an error, he's like a real developer trying to fix it, and let's see the result,
how it will be it, okay, he's adding some of the files, so let's wait a bit, so we can click on any file,
click open deep and you will see what was updated, okay, so we can click on the common
pattern on possible strands, you see the import was updated, and beat on the rest is same, okay,
of the tastes, file it, yep, as you see he did iterations, he faced with the files at all,
he'd been trying to fix it, then he ran test again, this is why I recommend you to enable
outrun to not always manually run it or copy paste the commands, oh, and then he'll see the
result and fail it, this he's trying to fix it, he's to face the test need to be adjusted to
refine the current behavior of the class, so let's wait a bit, let's see, he also created some
Babel config, just file it, okay, that's the file with mode version to use and what resets for
transparency of code to use, okay, now he's you see all the tests is pass it, so he did a fix, so we
took three iterations, as I see, and now he's providing a summary, okay, create all the tests on our
passing, there is a summary, and he's explaining what he did, he set up just testing environment,
he created this test cases, he also, what he did, fix the test case to match the actual implementation,
sometimes he can do it wrong for the first attempt, he verifies all the tests of passing, and now
he provides a test use, oh, we can click accept all, or of course, yeah, we can click accept one by one,
like you see there are one change we click accept, and accept another change, so but it's,
if you want to do it manually, or for some special, you see when it hover on another block,
I see also accept, so I would recommend you to accept all the changes right now, and now we can run
tests with NPM test command, let's check it by our cell, yeah, everything works, okay, this is great,
yeah, so, and now we spent about five minutes to write all the tests with AI, he did iterations
to fix it, so now you know how to use write mode, and for what use cases, you can use it,
and see you in the next lesson, where I will tell you how to use the plan mode, also nice features
from them in surfing.